  {
    "year1Ques": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "____________ is the type of clock display numerical digit.",
        "options": ["Digital clock", "Analog clock", "Wristwatch"],
        "answer": "Digital clock"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "_______ supply power into the digital wrist watch.",
        "options": ["Battery", "Water", "Milk"],
        "answer": "Battery"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "_________ monitor shows colours.",
        "options": ["Colour Monitor", "Monochrome monitor", "None of the above"],
        "answer": "Colour Monitor"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "_________ is a small device that perform arithmetic operation on number.",
        "options": ["Stopwatch", "Calculator", "Home"],
        "answer": "Calculator"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "________ is needed before you can start making, receiving calls and message with your mobile phone.",
        "options": ["Sim", "Video", "Films"],
        "answer": "Sim"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Which is not an ICT device.",
        "options": ["Pencil", "GSM phone", "Digital wristwatch"],
        "answer": "Pencil"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "The mouse has how many button?",
        "options": ["Two", "Four", "Five"],
        "answer": "Two"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "A computer makes work_______ .",
        "options": ["Easy and Faster", "Stronger", "Sharper"],
        "answer": "Easy and Faster"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Digital wristwatch shows time as _______________.",
        "options": ["Letters", "Numbers", "Words"],
        "answer": "Numbers"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Addition and subtraction of digits can be done using _______________.",
        "options": ["Calculators", "Water", "Paper"],
        "answer": "Calculators"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "question": "__________ is a wireless handheld device used for making and receiving calls and text messages.",
        "options": ["Mobile phones", "Cars", "Televisions"],
        "answer": "Mobile phones"
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "question": "_______ is used for typing.",
        "options": ["Keyboard", "Mouse", "Monitor"],
        "answer": "Keyboard"
      },
      {
        "id": 13,
        "question": "Computer is used for ________ in the hospital.",
        "options": ["Scanning", "Counting", "Singing"],
        "answer": "Scanning"
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "question": "What looks like a television? ______",
        "options": ["Keyboard", "Monitor", "Mouse"],
        "answer": "Monitor"
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "question": "______ is used to type a letter.",
        "options": ["Mouse", "Keyboard", "UPS"],
        "answer": "Keyboard"
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "question": "______ can be used to play computer game.",
        "options": ["Leg", "UPS", "Joystick"],
        "answer": "Joystick"
      },
      {
        "id": 17,
        "question": "It is a MUST to have a UPS to help protect your computer.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": "True"
      },
      {
        "id": 18,
        "question": "_______ is an electronic machine that accepts data.",
        "options": ["Computer", "Keyboard", "Machine"],
        "answer": "Computer"
      },
      {
        "id": 19,
        "question": "A digital wristwatch works like a computer.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": "True"
      },
      {
        "id": 20,
        "question": "Calculator is a common ICT device.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": "True"
      }
    ]
  }
  